Michael Plunkett

Front End Development UI/UX

(he/him)

- michael@mrplunkett.com
- mrplunkett.com
- github.com/mister-blanket

about

I have spent my adult life marrying my passion for helping people with a deep undertanding of technology. I have taught children with Autism to compose electronic music, I have helped medical students adapt to new learning environments and I have played a part in transforming the Sally Beauty E-Commerce platform into an accessible, intuitive experience.

work experience

Sally Beauty

2020 - present Denton, Texas

Manager, Front End Development (2022)

Developed and implemented a streamlined workflow & QA process, giving the dev team greater agility in responding to changing business needs.

Senior Front End Developer

Innovated automations to improve site performance and reduce build time.

Worked with partners to implement experiments, which reduced bounce rate and increased conversion and RPV.

portfolio

blood lines is a 3D family tree visualizer built with React & D3

soil is a travel map, made with ES6 & Google Maps API

see more

Mr. Plunkett

2018 - present Dallas, Texas

Front End Developer

Developed and launched an international multi-lingual ecommerce platform.

Produced business sites for clients with a focus on mobile first, SEO, accessibility and clean UI design.

skills

JavaScript (ES6) | React | Node | NPM | Webpack | Git | HTML | CSS | Sass | Salesforce | Photoshop | XD | Figma

St. George's University of London

2015 - 2017 London, U.K.

IT Support Analyst

Worked with SQL and Dev team in database debugging.

Wrote Visual Basic for Applications (VBA) code to improve auditing workflow & documentation.

education

B.M., Music Therapy

Arizona State University

Gateway Academy

2006 - 2014 Scottsdale, AZ

Director of Music

Improved student computer literacy through creating and leading a digital music program.